James Ebentier, Staff Software Engineer at Invoca

jebentier@gmail.com | +49 (0) 175 1060289 | Berlin, Berlin, DE jamesebentier.com | github.com/jebentier | linkedin.com/in/jebentier | twitter.com/jebentier

SUMMARY

Staff Software Engineer with a primary focus on efficiently and effectively transfering data between systems. Over the past 10 years of my career I've mastered skills across the Data Processing, Streaming, Infrastructure Provisioning, Automation, Service Oriented Architecture Design and Software Development.

EXPERIENCE

Invoca, Staff Software Engineer

2018-03-01 — Present

https://www.invoca.com/

- o Invoca is an AI-powered call tracking and analytics platform that helps marketers get campaign attribution and actionable data from inbound phone calls. Invoca delivers real-time call analytics to help marketers take informed actions based on data generated before and during a phone converstation. As a Staff Software Engineer at Invoca, I was responsible for being a technical leader not only on my scrum team, but to the Engineering department as a whole. I was not just responsible for coding solutions for complex problems, but also planning ahead and designing scalable, fault talerent systems for processing call data sent from out telecom systems in real time.
- Identified key areas of strain on internal systems, created a roadmap for upgrade and development work, and delivered to completion through the work of my team
- Work cross team and cross department to understand and solve company needs outside of feature development
- Contributed heavily on sales initiatives that needed special engineering guidance during the implementation process
- Designed and implemented an in-house auto-scaling centralized logging solution capable of processing upwards of 1 billion log lines a day with < 20 seconds of latency using Filebeat/Logstash, Kafka, Elasticsearch, and Kibana.
- Trained developers on how to use common production investigation tools like Kibana, grep, MySQL, gdb
- Developed an open source structured logging gem that is now used across the entire platform for more detailed log aggregation in Elasticsearch
- Designed the roadmap for and lead my team on rebuilding our data webhooks infrastructure to be more scalable and follow SOA best practices
- Designed and lead a cross team initiative to convert the communication between our telecom systems and data warehouse from REST API calls to Kafka streams and Event Driven Design

Invoca, Senior Software Engineer

2016-02-01 — 2018-03-01

https://www.invoca.com/

- As a Senior Software Engineer at Invoca I was responsible for being a technical leader on my team. Performing Code Reviews and teaching the other developers best practices. It was expected of me to privide simple, elegant, and fully tested solutions to complex problems at fast speeds.
- Developed a SlackBot responsible for automating the deployment process
- Converted all system from using a Chef provisioned YAML file to Consul and Consul Template for service discovery
- o Converted all system from using a Chef provisioned YAML file to Vault for application secrets
- Gained an understanding for the ins and outs of the telecom infrastructure and performed regular fixes and upgrades to these system
- o Pushed company practices from bi-weekly deployments to multiple deployments per day

Graphiq Inc., Senior Software Engineer

https://www.graphiq.com/

- o Graphiq (formerly FindTheBest) is a semantic technology company that instantly delivers deep insights from the world's data. Since 2010, the company has amassed the world's deepest and most interconnected knowledge graph, encompassing 500 collections, 1 billion entitites, 250 billion data points and 25 billion curated relationships. At Graphiq I was responsible for building and maintianing the main data pipeline in the platform used by the company to injest, process, and store data within the knowledge graph.
- Implemented and managed Kafka infrustructure used for streaming data updates into one of the world's largest knowledge graphs.
- Utilized service oriented architecture principles to improve speed and effeciency of both the data pipeline, and development.
- Built automated deploy pipelines for various pieces of the platform not just limited to the data pipeline
- Developed API documentation and SDKs using OpenAPI for easy distribution and usage throughout the company
- o Became a main contributor to the OpenAPI open source project
- Developed a Pentaho Kettle plugin to allow ETL processes to seemlessly stream data into the platform

Novacoast, Developer III

2011-06-01 - 2013-10-01

https://www.novacoast.com/

- Novacoast is a security and software development consultant company headquartered in Santa Barbara, California. The services that Novacoast offered are geared toward enterprise and Fortune 500 companies. As a Developer III at Novacoast I worked on many different contracts ranging from software and infrastructure security consultanting, urgent incident response teams, to beta application development for local start ups.
- o Developed multiple demo applications for clients used for sales purposes
- o Performed and communicated the findings of penetration tests against a wide range of systems
- Installed security infrastructure ranging from Web Application Firewalls to Symantec System Monitoring platforms
- o Developed and installed custom CRM and Active Directory management platforms

Dekka-Tek, Web Development Intern

2010-01-01 - 2010-06-01

Dekka-Tek was a think tank used to ideate and create new startups in the Santa Barbara,
California area. As an intern at Dekka-Tek I worked with Bob Wilson and Derrek Allef to build out an online platform to be used by the US Judo community for managing tournament registration and tracking.

EDUCATION

University of California Santa Barbara

2007-09-01 — 2012-06-01

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science

SKILLS

Daily Toolbelt (Master): Ruby/Rails, Node.js/Javascript/JQuery/React, CSS/HTML, Kafka/KafkaConnect/KSQL, RabbitMQ/Cellary, Percona/MySQL/PostgreSQL/MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Logstash/BeatLib/Kibana, Python, Docker/Kubernetes, Jenkins, bash/sh/*nix, Chef/Ansible/Terraform, Graphite/Graphana/StatsD, Distributed Trace/Jeager, AWS/GCE, Redis, Vault/Consul

Other Programing Languages (Intermediate): Java/Scala, PHP, R, Go, C/C++

Techniques (Advanced): Configuration Management, Continuous Integration / Deployment, Test Driven Development, Agile/Scrum/Kanbahn, Continuous Improvement, Service Oriented Architecture, Distributed Systems, Event Driven Architecture

LANGUAGES

English (Native Speaker=)